Guide to the Promenade Into the Past Photograph Album
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Promenade into the past photograph album
1891-1977
1937-1977
A0026
Guthrie, Luell W.
2.75 Linear feet (9 volumes)
Photographs, articles, clippings, brochures, programs, and other items pertaining to women at Stanford (Jane Stanford, wives of the University Presidents, Mary Yost, and early students); women's sports; skiing, both dry-skiing classes at Stanford and ski trips to Yosemite; recreation; women's intercollegiate tennis; and gymnastics. The volumes on skiing include original photographs taken for an article on the women's dry-skiing class that appeared in LIFE, 1945.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Luell W. Guthrie.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Guthrie taught physical education at Stanford University from 1936 until her retirement in 1972, when she was appointed professor emerita.
Description of the Collection
Photographs, articles, clippings, brochures, programs, and other items pertaining to women at Stanford (Jane Stanford, wives of the University Presidents, Mary Yost, and early students); women's sports; skiing, both dry-skiing classes at Stanford and ski trips to Yosemite; recreation; women's intercollegiate tennis; and gymnastics. The volumes on skiing include original photographs taken for an article on the women's dry-skiing class that appeared in LIFE, 1945.
Access Terms
Guthrie, Luell W.; Stanford University. Department of Athletics.; Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905.; Yost, Mary.; Albums.; Photoprints.; Sports for women.; Women--California.
Collection Contents
- Photograph Albums
  - Volume I The First Ladies of Stanford [wives of the presidents, Jane L. Stanford, Mary Yost, early students and others]: photographs, clippings, postcards, 1894-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Volume IIA Women’s Sports: early history (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Volume IIA Women’s Sports: hockey (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Volume IIA Women’s Sports: gymnastics (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Volume IIA Women’s Sports: bicycling (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Volume IIA Women’s Sports: tennis (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Volume IIA Women’s Sports: basketball (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Volume IIA Women’s Sports: fencing (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Volume IIA Women’s Sports: equitation (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Volume IIB Women’s Sports: archery (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Volume IIB Women’s Sports: golf (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Volume IIB Women’s Sports: badminton, softball (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Volume IIB Women’s Sports: volleyball (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Volume IIB Women’s Sports: aquatics (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Volume IIB Women’s Sports: track & field (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Volume IIB Women’s Sports: history (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Volume IIB Women’s Sports: faculty (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Volume IIB Women’s Sports: 1931 building [Roble Gym] (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Volume III, Part 1 Ski Conditioning: intro materials (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Volume III, Part 1 Ski Conditioning: photographs (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Volume III, Part 1 Ski Conditioning: photographs and 1 clipping (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Volume III, Part 2 Skiing at Yosemite: photographs (1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Volume III, Part 2 Skiing at Yosemite: photographs (2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Volume III, Part 2 Skiing at Squaw Valley and Sun Valley: photographs (3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Volume IV Recreation: John Almack article and others 1970 and undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Volume IV Recreation: Summer Recreation Schedules 1953-61 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Volume IV Recreation: Booklets, programs, etc. 1937-68 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Volume IV Recreation: Bibliography on leisure by Rolf Meyersohn 1958 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Volume V Tennis Intercollegiates: photos, 1964-65 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Volume V Tennis Intercollegiates: photos, misc. printed matter, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Volume V Tennis Intercollegiates: printed matter from national championship 1966 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Volume V Tennis Intercollegiates: photos, misc. printed matter, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Volume VI Gymnastics: paper by Mona Lisa Englund on Swedish Ballexercises with photos of her demonstrating routines ca. 1960 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Volume VI Gymnastics: Rhythmic Gymnastics Information Sheet by Chris Knauer, Ball Routine by Barbara Helsingius (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Program from USLTA Women’s Collegiate Championships, Stanford University, June 1966 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Journal of Health Physical Education Recreation (includes Leisure Today), March 1972 and June 1973 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Sports Illustrated, Dec. 26, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Assorted articles, 1960-72, and Stanford Women’s Sports Calendar 1968 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Volume III, Part 3 Dry-skiing at Stanford: original photographs taken for a Life magazine story, 1945 (Box 4)